One steals. One kills. One dies.
The Missouri Breaks is a western, drama film directed by Arthur Penn.
When vigilante land baron David Braxton hangs one of the best friends of cattle rustler Tom Logan,
Logan's gang decides to get even by purchasing a small farm next to Braxton's ranch.
From there the rustlers begin stealing horses, using
the farm as a front for their operation.
Determined to stop the thefts at any cost, Braxton retains the
services of eccentric sharpshooter Robert E.
Lee Clayton, who begins ruthlessly taking down Logan's gang.
Robert E. Lee Clayton, played by Marlon Brando.
Tom Logan, played by Jack Nicholson.
Tittle Tod, played by Randy Quaid.
Jane Braxton, played by Kathleen Lloyd.
Cary, played by Frederic Forrest.
Calvin, played by Harry Dean Stanton.
The Missouri Breaks is a 1976 American Western film
starring Marlon Brando and Jack Nicholson.
The film was directed by Arthur Penn, with supporting performances by Randy Quaid, Harry Dean
Stanton, Frederic Forrest, John McLiam, and Kathleen Lloyd in her film debut.
The score was composed by John Williams.
The title of the film refers to a forlorn and very rugged area of  north-central Montana, where
over eons, the Missouri River has made countless deep cuts or "breaks" in the land.
The film explores themes including the American frontier
myth, economic exploitation and law and order.
Like some other films directed by Penn, it has been read as an
allegory of capitalism and the American counterculture.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.